<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Study on Thoughts, Views &amp; More...</title>
    <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/categories/study/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Study on Thoughts, Views &amp; More...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 17:44:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.fahadahammed.com/categories/study/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Again Fibonacci Series and Python</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/again-fibonacci-series-and-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 17:44:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/again-fibonacci-series-and-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have already wrote a piece about generating Fibonacci series in &lt;strong&gt;BASH&lt;/strong&gt;, here in my blog. But today I am gonna do some practice stuff with &lt;strong&gt;Python&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all I guess know about &lt;strong&gt;Fibonacci&lt;/strong&gt;. It is connected to nature through the golden ratio and the spirals. It is a very interesting series to learn or research deeply. However, I came to know that there is a day declared as “&lt;strong&gt;Fibonacci Day&lt;/strong&gt;” which is every 23rd, November. But why?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prestressed Concrete Concepts and Classification</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/prestressed-concrete-concepts-and-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 09:35:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/prestressed-concrete-concepts-and-classification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prestressed Concrete:&lt;/strong&gt; Prestressed concrete is a method for overcoming concrete’s natural weakness in tension. It can be used to produce beams, floors or bridges with a longer span than is practical with ordinary reinforced concrete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of the Design and Construction activities of the Maghbazar-Mouchak Inter-change (Flyover) Project</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/an-overview-of-the-design-and-construction-activities-of-the-maghbazar-mouchak-inter-change-flyover-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2014 16:18:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/an-overview-of-the-design-and-construction-activities-of-the-maghbazar-mouchak-inter-change-flyover-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction:&lt;/strong&gt; Bangladesh has got its independence in 1971. 42 years have passed and its population is growing from 3.7642 billion to 7.0439 billion. We have improved our life style by urbanization and agricultural success with industrialization. But people of Bangladesh are city-centric.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Draw an Involute Curve From a Given Circle</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/draw-an-involute-curve-from-a-given-circle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 18:09:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/draw-an-involute-curve-from-a-given-circle/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drawing an Involute Curve is a tough one to draw. I will give you tips to draw easily. Involute is very important in Gear industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell Script to Generate Fibonacci Series Iteratively and Recursively</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/shell-script-to-generate-fibonacci-series-iteratively-and-recursively/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 05:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/shell-script-to-generate-fibonacci-series-iteratively-and-recursively/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By definition, the first two Fibonacci numbers are 0 and 1, and each subsequent number is the sum of the previous two. I will show you two shell script to generate Fibonacci series recursively and iteratively. Also you will get idea about the application of Fibonacci series/numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Bridges</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/types-of-bridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2014 01:49:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/types-of-bridges/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bridges are a very important structure of a society or civilization. A bridge can connect people and can improve the life of people by giving numerous opportunities including many business sector. However, I am here to describe different types of bridges. I have collected this information from Wikipedia and other sites. You will definitely learn something interesting. I was researching this as my course teacher asked me to submit an assignment paper about Types of Bridges and their little information including pictures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road Marking and Street Lighting</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/road-marking-and-street-lighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 17:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/road-marking-and-street-lighting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Road traffic crashes are one of the world’s largest public health and injury prevention problems. The problem is all the more acute because the victims are overwhelmingly healthy prior to their crashes. According to the World Health Organization (WHO), more than a million people are killed on the world’s roads each year. I am writing this article to make you well acquainted with street safety factors and how street lights and markings will cause a relief from grief of a family.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Civil Engineering Softwares List</title>
      <link>https://www.fahadahammed.com/civil-engineering-softwares-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 14:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.fahadahammed.com/civil-engineering-softwares-list/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;3D Nature’s World Construction Set&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
– photorealistic 3D terrain visualization for cartography,&lt;br&gt;
architecture, civil engineering, golf, forestry and land planning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;3D Structural Modeling Software – 3D+&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;br&gt;
-An AutoCAD based parametric modeling, analysis, design and drawing system for structural engineers. Includes program description with downloadable videos. Offers online ordering and technical support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
