<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scripts on Thoughts, Views &amp; More...</title>
    <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/tags/scripts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scripts on Thoughts, Views &amp; More...</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 09:06:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fahadahammed.github.io/tags/scripts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finding an Efficient Solution on Reading and Comparing CSV files</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/finding-an-efficient-solution-on-reading-and-comparing-csv-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 09:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/finding-an-efficient-solution-on-reading-and-comparing-csv-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always worked with Linux Systems and thus Bash was my go to tool for some specific tasks. But now I am much more aware with Python than Bash as it does give me better grasp on things. I am not saying that for server scripting, Bash can not do some tasks. It can be used in a vast area of things to solve. But I am now comfortable with Python more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I did stumble upon of a task that was related to comparing two huge CSV files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSH Config and Ansible Host Generator and Why I am doing it this way?</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/ssh-config-and-ansible-host-generator-and-why-i-am-doing-it-this-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 14:50:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/ssh-config-and-ansible-host-generator-and-why-i-am-doing-it-this-way/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am recently playing the role as an SRE and that is why I have to deal with a lot of servers. Not only cloud once or clusters but also bare metals as well as Virtual Machines. For more systematic environment preparation, I have Gitlab pipeline. But for basic tasks like change the config on demand or check a specific directory or search something or any other unpredictable or repeated tasks, I need Ansible for better grasp from my local machine or Bastion server. So, what do I have to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an entry to the .ssh/config file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create an entry ansible host file as inventory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repeated tasks? For me, yes. I needed to manage these. So, created a python script&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Batch Script to Put Ping Output in a Text File</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/windows-batch-script-to-put-ping-output-in-a-text-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2014 08:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/windows-batch-script-to-put-ping-output-in-a-text-file/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In DOS, OS/2, and also Microsoft Windows, batch file is the name given to a type of script file, a text file containing a series of commands to be executed by the command interpreter. A batch file may contain any command the interpreter accepts interactively at the command prompt. A batch file may also have constructs (IF, GOTO, Labels, CALL, etc.) that enable conditional branching and looping within the batch file. Recently i was playing with it and got a cool script while playing with ping command which will output ping results in a text file in Desktop.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell Script to Generate Fibonacci Series Iteratively and Recursively</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/shell-script-to-generate-fibonacci-series-iteratively-and-recursively/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2014 05:52:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/shell-script-to-generate-fibonacci-series-iteratively-and-recursively/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By definition, the first two Fibonacci numbers are 0 and 1, and each subsequent number is the sum of the previous two. I will show you two shell script to generate Fibonacci series recursively and iteratively. Also you will get idea about the application of Fibonacci series/numbers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Command to Download and Install All Bangla Fonts in Your Linux</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/single-command-to-download-and-install-all-bangla-fonts-in-your-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 13:37:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/single-command-to-download-and-install-all-bangla-fonts-in-your-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have created a script which will download and install 70 Bangla fonts(with variations of them) without searching. Just run this script in your Linux based PC/Laptops terminal and get all Bangla fonts instantly without hassle.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shell Script to Test Your VPS or Servers Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/shell-script-to-test-your-vps-or-servers-efficiency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 07:22:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/shell-script-to-test-your-vps-or-servers-efficiency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Server lover like me and you will always try our best to get the full performance from our VPS/Server. Here is a script to show you some interesting thing about your server including download speed from popular Data Center, cpu model, frequency, ram, swap, Uptime I/O Speed etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SolusVM API PHP Script</title>
      <link>https://fahadahammed.github.io/solusvm-api-php-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2014 06:53:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fahadahammed.github.io/solusvm-api-php-script/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The client API is a http based API that allows you and your clients to interact directly with a virtual server with security and ease. The client API can be disabled at any time and access is only granted with a key and hash on a per vps basis.Currently available options are:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
